

Nicolas Zhang

Profile

A motivated and creative incoming first-year student with excellent analytical and problem-solving skills. A very quick learner with great attention to detail, immensely passionate about scientific research and exercise science. A well-rounded team player with great organizational and coordinating abilities, dedicated to pursuing higher-level research and professional experiences.

Employment History

Research Internship, North Carolina State University

MARCH 2022 - JANUARY 2023

Researched at the Micro/Nano Engineering Lab under Dr. Xiaoning Jiang. Assisted group research project on real-time clot detection for sonothrombolysis catheter. Conducted individual research on helical magnetic field generation.

Kumon assistant manager, Kumon of Farm Woods

MAY 2022 - MARCH 2023

Responsible for data entry, organizing class resources, and tutoring students. Led, coordinated, and mentored other assistants in daily operations.

Education

Green Hope High School, Cary

Cumulative GPA Weighted 4.60; Unweighted 3.97.

35 on the ACT

University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill

First-year

Extra-curricular activities

Youth Group Leader, Cary Chinese School

SEPTEMBER 2020 - PRESENT

Coordinated and delivered groceries and COVID supplies in the local community. Persisted through quarantine to assist struggling families.

Vice president, Green Hope Physics Bowl

SEPTEMBER 2021 - JUNE 2022

Planned weekly meetings, prepared slides and admitted members. Co-led and organized review sessions and discussions. Competed in AATP Physics Bowl.

Red Cross Club, Green Hope High School

SEPTEMBER 2021 - PRESENT

Volunteering at various events and organizations such as Hemophilia of NC, Note in the Pocket clothing drive, etc, to improve human wellness.

Varsity indoor Track & Field, Green Hope High School

SEPTEMBER 2021 - FEBRUARY 2022

Team Carolina AAU Basketball, Hoops City U

Details

9193603377

weiyang@unc.edu

Languages

English

Chinese

Hobbies

Weight lifting, basketball, swimming, photography, cooking.

Courses

AP Calculus AB

AP Calculus BC

AP Physics 1

AP Physics 2

AP Physics C: Mechanics

AP Computer Science A

AP Computer Science Principles

AP Human Geography

AP Environmental Science

AP Statistics

Calculus III (MA 242), North Carolina State University

Microeconomics (ECO 251), Wake Tech Community College

Macroeconomics (ECO 252), Wake Tech Community College

Introduction to Business (BUS 110), Wake Tech Community College

Introduction to Sociology (SOC 210), Wake Tech Community College

Introduction to Interpersonal Communication (COM 120), Wake Tech Community College

Entrepreneurship I (BUS 139), Wake Tech Community College